Back in those days,
to travel meant to risk your life.
この時代、旅とは文字通り命懸けであった。
遭難、追い剥ぎだけでなく
You could get lost or robbed.
怪我や病気も即命取りとなる。
Injuries or illnesses could
easily prove fatal.
旅の途中で消息を絶つことは決して珍しくなかったのである
So it was not uncommon for travelers to
vanish without trace.
やろうか？
You want...?
おや？こいつは…
Oh? My, my.
Party is over
But I still wanna dance
I can't even sleep
Someday, one day my passion's fire will
From the beginning I knew
One day the flames would die out
Hey, I thought I didn't need anything
But even now, I'm so serious
Ah... I still have time to make it
Ah... but I'm gonna burn it up, baby
Sorry darling, it's not that easy
But surely it's not that bad either
Give me fire
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
Party is over
Sorry darling Hurry up
Ah... I still have time to make it
Give me fire
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
#2 The story of Bandai
You can see. I knew it.
やっぱ見えてる。どう考えても見えてるって！
You can see, right?
なぁ、見えてるんだろ？
How else could you fight a monster
like you just did?
でなきゃバケモンとあんなふうに戦えるわけねぇって！
You were so cool.
You shouldn't let it go to waste.
すげぇ強かったもんなぁ！
その腕、タダで転がしておいちゃもったいねぇ！
You could...
なんかこう…
Hey, are you listening?
おい！おいってば！
Do you go around slaying monsters?
いつもああやってバケモン退治してんのか？
How is that sword fixed to your arm?
その腕の剣、どうやってついてんだ？
And this.
それからコレ
It fell off your face,
and some new skin grew.
あんたの顔から落ちて、新しい顔が生えた
This thing is fake,
こいつはよく見りゃ作りモンだけど…
but your new skin is real, isn't it?
今のアンタの皮は本物…だろ？
How'd you do that?
どうなってんだ？
Hey, you listening?
聞けよ！
I knew you could see.
うん…完全に見えてるだろそれ。
What, you don't want to talk to me?
なんでだよ？オイラと話したくないのか？
Why...
どうしてだ…
Woah! I'm sorry, I'll get off your case.
わっ！待てよ！ごめん、しつこすぎた
Wow.
すげぇ…
Woah! Stop, stop.
わっ！待て待て待て！
You shouldn't eat it raw. Wait a sec.
生はよくねぇって！少し待ってなよ
How about it? Smells good, huh?
ほら！うまそうな匂いがしてきたろ？
It'd be even better with salt.
塩があるといいんだがなぁ…
But this'll do. Here ya go.
まぁ、しょうがねぇ。ほらよ
Sometimes it seems like
you really can't see.
はぁ…そうしてると本当に見えてねぇって風だよな。
You can't hear or talk, either.
耳も聞こえず口も聞けねぇ…
You're so strange, you know that?
ホント不思議なやつだよなぁ、あんた
Oh well.
まぁいいや…
Don't you want to make some money?
なぁ。あんたその腕、金にしねぇか？
Leave it to me, and I'll make you rich.
You could even be a millionaire.
おいらに任せりゃ絶対稼げる。
お大尽だって夢じゃねぇ
You think so too,
that's why you don't shoo me away.
な？あんただってそう思ってるからおいらを
追い払わねぇんだ。そうだろ？
Hyakkimaru could not see nor hear Dororo.
百鬼丸にはどろろの姿も声も届いてはいない。
But there was something
he could "see" ever since he was born.
だが、百鬼丸には生まれながらに見えているものがある
The fire of the soul, shall we say.
魂の炎、とでも言うほかない
The key was the color.
重要なのは、その色だった
Hostility, hatred,
and beings not of this world.
敵意、憎悪、またはこの世ならざるもの
Hyakkimaru detected such dangers
by their colors.
それらの持つ色が百鬼丸に危険を教える
As well as this power, he also possessed
superhuman senses and strength.
魂の色を見る力。
そして、常人ではない間隔と身体能力によって
This was how he survived the darkness
in which he lived.
百鬼丸は彼の暗闇の中を生きてきたのである
Hyakkimaru let Dororo stay close,
今、百鬼丸がどろろを放っておくのは
only because the color of his soul
did not indicate danger.
その炎の色が危険ではないからということでしかない。
Even so...
ただ
Here. This small one's for me
because I cooked it for you.
ほら、この小さいのはおいらの焼き賃
This soul didn't pass him by,
but remained close.
通り過ぎることなく、長く自分のそばに留まる炎は
It was the second soul to do so.
彼にとって2つめだった
Stop...
やめろ…
Don't...
やめてくれ…
Mama!
おっかちゃん！
Did I say something in my sleep?
おいら、なんか寝言言ったかい？
Oh yeah.
そっか…
You can't hear me.
聞こえねぇもんな…
Can't you at least tell me your name?
なぁ、名前くらい教えてくれよ。
I'm Dororo. Do-ro-ro.
おいらはどろろだ。どーろーろ
You?
あんたは？
Guess not. You're Mr. No-name then.
って、無理か。いいや！もう名無しの権兵衛で。
Goodnight.
おやすみー
Hey!
Listen up!
I just heard about something
that we could make money with.
早速あんたの腕で稼げる話を聞いてきた！とにかくちょっと！
It seems like there's a monster
haunting a village.
この先の村にバケモンが出るらしいんだ。
Villagers and travelers who stop by
disappear now and then.
村に立ち寄った旅人とか、
村の人がときどき行方知れずになっちまうらしい。
You're going to beat it
like you did before and get a reward.
そいつをこないだみたいに退治して礼金を貰うんだよ
We save people and get money doing it.
Great, huh?
人助けしておいらたちも儲かる。な？いい考えだろ？
Seems like a pretty rich village.
へぇー。なんだか金持ちそうな村だなぁ。
There's really a monster here?
ホントにバケモンなんか出るのかなぁ？
Did somebody say monster?
はて、バケモンとおっしゃいましたか？
What about a monster?
化け物がどうかしましたか？
Don't assume I don't know.
へへっ、どうかしたのはこの村だろ？
We heard you're in trouble.
知ってるぜ、困ってるって
Got some great news for ya.
いい話を持ってきてやったんだ
This guy right here
is the best at slaying monsters.
なんとこのお兄さん！バケモン退治にかけちゃ天下一品。
How about it?
ひとつ頼ってみなよ
Can he really do it?
本当にそんなことができますので？
As sure as anything.
大出来だよ！
Just the other day, he beat up
this huge monster into little bits.
こないだもこーんなでけぇバケモンをたーった
1人で細切れにしちまったのを、
I saw it with my own eyes.
個の目で見たばっかりだよ
So how about it?
Can't hurt to give us a shot.
どうよ、頼むだけならタダだ。
Got nothing to lose, right?
騙されたと思ってさ、な？
How fortunate that you came.
それはもう願ってもないことで。
If you'll slay it for us,
the village will do much to repay you.
退治していただけるなら、村でできるかぎりのお礼を
Right, everyone?
なぁ、皆の衆
I like the way you talk, Chief.
いやぁ～、話が早いねぇ村長さん
I'm just filling in for the chief.
My name is Denkichi.
あぁいえ、私は名代を務めます伝吉と申す者で…
Our chief's name is Bandai.
村の長は万代というお方なのですが、
She has injured her legs and can't move.
なにぶん足を悪くされまして
Anyways, please feel free
to stay at my home.
とにかく、私どものうちをお使いください。
I don't have much to offer,
but would you like some supper?
大したものもございませんが、お食事など…
I really like the way you talk.
おぉっ！いや、ホント話が早いねぇ
Come this way.
こちらでございます
This is like paradise.
くぅ～、極楽極楽。
I haven't eaten so much for ages.
いや～、こんなに食べたの久しぶりだぁ
But they're pretty flashy
for a village troubled by a monster.
でもさ…バケモンに困ってる割に贅沢な暮らししてるよな。
They don't have
a lot of rice paddies, either.
見たとこ大した田んぼもなかったし…
How do they make so much money?
なんで儲けてんだろうなぁ
Monster!
出たぁーっ！
Monster, right over there!
おい！そこにいるよ！
In front of you, get him!
目の前！こないだみたいにやっつけてくれよ！
Hey, come on, hurry.
おい…何してんだよ、早く！
You want...?
やろうか…？
See? He wants to fight.
Hold on, you'll get what you want.
ほら、やるかって言ってる。待ってろ、今やってやる！
Hurry, take your arm off.
早く…この手、抜かねぇと…
Come on...
早く…
Hurry up!
おい、早くしろよ…！
What? Hey, it's leaving!
えっ…！おい待て！行っちまうよ！
Hurry...
早く…！うぅ…！
Aww, jeez! It's gone.
あぁもう、何なんだよ！
Is something the matter?
あの…どうかなさいましたか？
Did you see the monster?
化け物は出ましたか？
Yeah, but we let it go for today.
Don't worry, we can handle it.
あ、いや…出たけど…今日は様子見だ。
うん…大したことなかった！
Is that so?
そうでございますか…
Good morning. Are you awake?
おはようございます。お目覚めでございますか？
Lady Bandai wishes to meet you two.
あの…万代さまがお2人にお目にかかりたいと…
Bandai? Oh yeah, the village chief.
万代？あぁ村長…
Yes, sorry we haven't even prepared
your breakfast yet.
はい、ご朝食も差し上げず申し訳ありませんが
Sure, no problem.
いいよ。わかった
That is her residence.
あちらの屋敷でございます
Wow.
すげぇ！
Good day.
では
Huh? It's really dark in here.
何だい、ずいぶん暗いな
I shall light a candle.
今、灯りを
Forgive me for being like this.
このようなお見苦しい姿、お許しを…
I can't use my legs.
足を患っておりますので
I am Bandai, the chief of this village.
私がこの村の長、万代でございます
Do I have something on my face, child?
坊や、私の顔に何か？
N-No, it's just you're really pretty.
い…いや、綺麗だなぁって
Oh my, thank you.
フ…恐れ入ります。
Forgive me for calling you to me.
お呼び立てして申し訳ございません。
I heard about you from the villagers
and had to meet you.
村人の話を聞いてどうしてもお会いしなければ、と…
Especially you.
特に、そこのお方。
I thought you might be, and I was right.
もしやと思っておりましたが、やはり…
Huh? You know him?
え？知ってるのかい？
What are you doing?
何をなさいます？
Hey, what's the matter?
おい、何するつもりだよ！
She's a human.
この人は人間だぞ！
Hey, stop it! What the heck?
待て…やめろ！どうしたんだよ！
-Lady Bandai!
-He's got a sword for an arm!
万代さま！
-こいつ腕から剣が生えてやがる！
Seize him!
早く取り押さえろ！
Stop it, she's no monster.
やめろ、あの人はバケモンじゃない…
Please stop!
おやめください！
-Watch it!
-Don't move.
待てぇ！
動くんじゃねぇ！
Take the boy, too.
そいつも仲間だ！
Hey, let go!
離せ！
Take them to the storehouse.
土蔵へ連れて行け！
What the heck? And you didn't
do anything to last night's monster.
どういうことだよ！
ゆんべのバケモンには指一本動かさねぇで…
She was a kind-looking lady.
あんな優しそうな人にいきなり斬りかかろうとしてさぁ
You really can't see, can ya!
わかったよ！あんたホンット見えてねぇ！
You don't see nothing!
なんも見えてねぇんだ！
It's quite lively today.
ずいぶんと賑やかだねぇ…
I'm glad to have some companions.
お仲間ができて嬉しいよ
Did you get caught too, Priest?
何だい？坊さん。あんたも捕まってんのか？
I heard there was a monster so I came to
see, and they locked me up in my sleep.
バケモンが出るってんで見物に来たら、
寝てる間に連れ込まれちまった
Why?
どうして？
Who knows? It could be a clue
to where all the people disappeared.
さぁてね…案外これが行方知れずの種明かしかもしれないねぇ
But anyways,
I've seen you before somewhere.
それより、お前さんには見覚えがある
Really? You can see?
見覚えって…目、見えるのか？
We see some things
people with sight can't see.
あたしらには、目明きには見えないものが見えたりするんでねぇ。
Sometimes, it's much more accurate, too.
そっちのほうがよっぽど確かだったりすることもあるのさ
You see things we can't see?
何だよ、見えないものが見えるって？
For example, you look like
a clear white flame to me.
例えば今あたしにゃ、お前さんが綺麗な真っ白い炎に見える
Flame?
炎…
Your soul, so to speak.
言ってみりゃ、魂さね。
We see what's on the inside,
not the outside.
見てくれじゃない、中身が見えるのさ
Soul? Inside?
魂…中身…
You mean this Mr. No-name
can see the way you do too?
あ、もしかしてこの名無しの権兵衛も坊さんみたいに見えるのか？
Maybe.
かもしれないねぇ
So when he drew his sword back there...
じゃあ、さっき刀抜いたのは…
Now what?
今度は何だよ！
Watch out.
気をつけ…
I sense something strange.
妙な気配だ
I can't see.
わっ！なんも見えねぇ！
Don't worry, we can't see anyway.
大丈夫、あたしらには同じことさ
What's happening? What was that voice?
どうなったんだ、今の声なんだよ！
Come with me.
いいからついておいで
It seems like this well
is connected to the outside.
どうやらこの井戸は外に通じているらしい
I can't see!
見えねぇよぉ！
No! I'm scared...
いやーっ！怖いー！
Don't worry. Feel that draft?
大丈夫。ほら、外の風だ
Huh? This place...
あれ？ここって…
There's your friend right there.
あそこにお連れがいるよ
Have you come to attack me again?
あぁ…また私を斬りにいらしたのですか？
Me, a sick woman. Why?
このような病人を一体なぜ…
Give it up. We only see
what's inside of you.
無駄だよ。あたしらにはお前さんの中身しか見えないんだ
What color?
色は？
Let's see.
そうさねぇ…今見えてるのは
What I see now is the murky color
of blood. The worst color of all.
どす黒い血のような赤。最悪の色だ
It's too bad I couldn't eat you
the first time.
さっき食いそこなったのは惜しかった
I'm sure you've realized it,
but this is something worse than a ghoul.
わかってるだろうな。
そんなやつは化け物なんて可愛いもんじゃない！
-It's a demon.
-A demon?
鬼神だ
-鬼神？
Doesn't that hurt?
痛くねぇのか？
Lady Bandai, run!
万代さま！お逃げください！
Hey, why'd you let it get away!
おい！なんでバケモン逃がすんだ！
What the heck is going on?
どういうつもりだよ
You knew about it, didn't you?
お前さん、知っていなすったな？
You knew,
and you fed the travelers to it.
知ってて旅人を食わせてたんだ
I had to, or else it would've eaten up
the villagers.
そうしなければ、あの化け物は村の者を食らいますんで…
That's why you wanted us to
slay it, right?
だからおいらたちに退治してほしかったんだろ？
If we defeat it,
then your problem's solved.
あいつを倒せばそれで解決じゃねぇか！
It seems like it wasn't Bandai
that he wanted slayed.
どうやら退治してほしかったのは万代じゃなかったようで
I knew it. You...!
間違いない…お前は！
To think you were still alive.
よもや生きていようとは…
It must be because
"it" failed to take you.
アレが奪いそこなった、そのせいか。
"It" was the only one
that couldn't get you.
アレだけがお前を取れなかった…
Have you come to get the rest back?
残りを取り戻す気か？
Interesting. Let's see if you can...
面白い、できるものなら…
Lady Bandai...
あぁっ…万代さまぁっ…！
You want...?
やろうかぁ…？やろうかぁ…？
It's him.
あいつ！
What's that?
なんだ？
Look, lots of money!
なんだこれ、大金だ！
Wow.
すげぇ！
The money of the travelers
you let Bandai eat, right?
万代に食わせた旅人の金だね？
What do you mean?
えっ？どういうことだよ？
Our village has nothing
to make money with.
うちの村は他に稼げるネタもなくて…
We thought everything was lost
when the monster Bandai took over.
化け物の万代さまに乗っ取られたときはもう終わりかと…
But the first traveler Lady Bandai ate
had a lot of road money on him.
でも最初に万代さまが食った旅人がかなりの路銀を持ってたもんで…
And you couldn't stop.
味を占めちまったってわけだね
Seriously? You guys are awful!
何だよ！それ最低じゃねぇか！
Even worse than monsters.
バケモンよりもっと…
Stop that sound, please!
ぐわぁっ…！止めてくれ！あの音を…！
Is that sound what you wanted us to slay?
お前さんが退治してほしかったのはあれかい？
It's the sound of the bell
that the first traveler carried...
最初に路銀を奪った旅人が持ってた…
A pilgrim's bell.
お遍路だったんだ…
Sorry for saying that stuff to you
when you tried to kill Bandai.
悪かったよ。万代斬ろうとしたあんたにひどいこと言って…
I was the one who was blind.
見えてなかったのはおいらだった…
You can't hear me.
聞こえてねぇか
He knows.
案外気持ちは通じるよ。
Don't let it get to you. It's natural
for those with sight to be tricked.
気にすることはない。目が見えてるもんなら、騙されて当然さ
She looked like her.
っていうか、似てたんだ…
Like my dead mama.
死んだおっかちゃんに、似てた
I see.
そうかい…
Huh, what now?
な…なんだよ急に！
Stop treating me like a kid,
you No-name!
ガキ扱いすんな！名無し野郎のくせに！
You can write?
なんだ？字が書けるのか…
Hey Priest, what did he write?
坊さん！なんて書いてあるのかわかるかい？
Let me feel it.
どれ、触れさせてくれるかい？
Hya-kki-maru. So that's your name.
ひゃっ…き…まる…あんたの名前だね？
Really? Hyakkimaru.
へぇー、百鬼丸！
I finally know your name. Hyakkimaru.
ははっ、やっとわかった。百鬼丸か
I know now, too.
No wonder I remember seeing you.
私もわかったよ。見覚えがあるはずだ
It was you on the river.
お前さん…あんときの…
What? Disquiet by the borders?
何？国境に不穏な動きだと？
Yes, they've increased
the number of soldiers on guard.
はっ。警護に当たる兵の数が増えております。
As if readying for war.
戦の準備ではと思われ…
Impossible. The Sakai Clan are our allies,
not just our neighbors.
馬鹿な！隣国の堺殿とは同盟の間柄…
I need you to investigate something.
そちに探ってもらうことがある
What's wrong?
どうしたんだよ！
Hey, are you in pain? Are you okay?
おい！痛いのか？
Hang in there!
なぁ！大丈夫かよ！しっかりしろよ、おい！
What's going on?
どうしたんだよ…なぁ！
"Bandai"